Guide to the Clifford Hildreth Papers, 1939-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Clifford Hildreth papers 1939-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Hildreth, Clifford, 1917-1995.
1.5 Linear Feet 350 Items
Economist; President of the American Statistical Association in 1973.
Collection primarily includes correspondence, writings, and print materials. These materials relate mostly to Clifford Hildreth's work as an economist as well as his roles as association president of the American Statistical Association (1973), and with the Cowles Commission in Chicago (1939-1955).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Clifford Hildreth Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1991-1994.
Biographical Note
Clifford Hildreth was professor of economics at Iowa State, the University of Chicago, North Carolina State University, Michigan State University, and University of Minnesota. He served as head of the Department of Economics at Michigan State, a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study of Behavioral Sciences at Stanford, and a Fulbright lecturer at the University of Tokyo, at the University of Kyoto, and at Hitotsubashi University in Japan. Hildreth wrote numerous articles on economics and statistics, was editor of the Journal of the American Statistical Association, as well as association president of the American Statistical Association in 1973.
Collection Overview
Collection primarily includes correspondence, writings, and print materials. These materials relate mostly to Clifford Hildreth's work as an economist as well as his roles as association president of the American Statistical Association (1973), and with the Cowles Commission in Chicago (1939-1955).
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Hildreth, Clifford, 1917-
Cowles Commission for Research in Economics
Economics -- Research
Economists
Contents of Collection
- Clifford Hildreth Papers, 1939-1995, (1 box)
  Includes correspondence, writings by Hildreth and others, print materials, and miscellaneous information. Materials primarily deal with Hildreth's work as an economist, as association president of the American Statistical Association, and his work with the Cowles Commission in Chicago. Materials are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - American Statistical Association, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, General, 1943-1992, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Cowles Commission, Correspondence, 1946-1985, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Cowles Commission, Discussion Papers, 1949-1953 (Box 1)
  - Cowles Commission, Print Materials, 1939-1955 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1952-1995 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Hildreth, 1942-1988, (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Writings, Others, 1949-1990, (2 folders) (Box 1)